[Music]
why is it so hard to make robots do
stuff
and i'm not talking about cute little
robots that you know
walk around and do simple things but
i'm talking about really complex systems
and these systems are composed by a lot
of subsystems
that need to work together and well they
need to work together well
since the problem is very complex let's
try to break it down
we can assume that robots are given a
set of simple skills
such as you know perceiving where an
object is through a perception system
or navigating from a point a to a point
b
while avoiding obstacles or some other
manipulation skills
like how to pick an object or how to
place it
now how can we combine these skills such
that robo can perform something
meaningful in the environment
my name is corado and i am a phd student
at the cognitive robotics department
and i'm also part of air lab the ai for
retail lab
my job is to research on how we can
combine the low level skills of
such complex systems in order to
reliably perform
tasks in environments that are designed
not for robots but
for humans like supermarkets
so let's say that the task of the robot
is to
stock an empty shelf well how should the
robot
plan and execute its actions to achieve
this goal
and this might sound simple for a human
but i guarantee you that it's very hard
in robotics
and you should know that it's very easy
for robots to fail in environments like
this one
do we for instance do errors in the
perception system
or just to unpredictable events that
might happen
what i'm trying to define in my work is
a control architecture to recover from
these kind of situations
and cope with them so i'm trying to
define a robot that has an adaptive
behavior
and i'm doing so based on active
inference a neuroscientific theory which
tries to explain
how the decision-making happens in our
brains the current state of my research
we can perform tasks that have some
variability
but i think we're still far from the
level of autonomy that we all dream of
however we're working hard to get there
in a responsible and a safe way
so that we can help our society to
advance
and well who knows maybe one day one of
these guys
will actually be part of our daily life
you